hey guys and welcome back to the rapado
Creek Railroad today I'm going to be
doing this quick product review of this
digit track Zephyr Express 3 amp starter
system for
DCC now before we get going here I'd
like to give a quick shout out to
Lombard Hobbies who I ordered this
product from they gave me some cool
stuff too with my order like this tote
bag some Welch's fruit snacks
and
also this which is an ho and inscale
track gauge so you can see on the sides
and the
bottom and
also a very well packaged order in
general with this box full of packing
peanuts and some bubble gra which is
currently stuck to my letter
thing okay so here's the DCC system and
just a bit of a disclaimer here I've I
actually got this a few weeks ago
already got it all hooked up to the
layout and all that and I've been
playing around with it and so far I've
been really happy so let's just switch
it on
here and when you start up you see this
startup screen with like some
information then it goes straight to the
th to the last like locomotive you had
put into the throttle as you can see
it's my number 566 the star of many of
my videos this little NW2 i Custom
lettered for the Rado Creek my fictional
Short Line in Western
Oregon now one of the things that I like
about this system is it comes with this
very really big quick start guide that's
got pictures and very detailed
instructions on everything you need to
know to get your system up and running
running fast so you can run trains it
even tells you how to run a DC
locomotive using this DCC
system so now let's go through some of
the basic functions right here you got
your just standard keypad your forward
brake
reverse like selector track status light
this button is track power on and off
and as you can
see the light will turn on and off
corresponding to the track power
status got your speed control there and
also right here you've got this is SE
for selecting a switch that's DCC
control the turnout turnout control and
this is your extended menu which will
bring up selections for stuff like CV
programming and quick decoder setup
which is another feature of this
system now another thing I like about
the controller is its General look and
feel all the components seem to be high
quality and I especially like how the
soft keys are back lit which would
definitely be helpful if I were to run
night operations and in lower light
where it's harder to see the numbers the
bless and the lines on the screen are
just an artifact of the video and
they're not actually present in real
life moving around to the back of the
system it's easy to set up with the
screw Terminals and expand I assume with
the locer net ports you can even use the
USB to connect it to your computer if
you
want now let's run a train with it this
is all in general a very user inuitive
process it's no harder really to control
a train than use a d power pack and with
just a little fiddling around you can
learn the functions pretty
quick even programming with this is a
breeze and you could almost just kind of
guess your way through without reading
the
manual now one big question for modelers
who want to get into DCC with one of
these starter systems is the digit TR
zeper or the nce power cab both are
similar systems both in price and basic
function and I can't really speak for
the NC one but the reason I went for the
digit Trak system is just because it's
newer and I wanted something that I felt
like a little bit more comfortable I was
buying something that's present and up
to
date other modelers might not really
have this concern but I have an old
issue of railroad model Craftsman from
the 9s and there is a picture for an ad
of an NC power Cab in there and I guess
that just put me off and I guess I
wanted to just to get something a little
bit that I felt was a little newer and
more up Tod dat but I can't really be
I'm not an expert though I am really
happy with this purchase and I would
definitely recommend it to other
modelers who are looking to get into DCC
for a relatively low price about the
price of a locomotive with
DCC okay so thanks for watching I hope
you like subscribe and comment below I'd
love to hear from you guys thanks for
watching see you in the next video
[Music]